EUGENE KIM

Johns Creek, GA 30097 • ekim1707@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/eugene-kim-1707

JAVASCRIPT SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Expert, disciplined learner of new technologies and languages as pertaining to software development project goals; passionately curious of all disciplines relating to progress and general welfare of the community. Strong grasp of agile work environments and flexibility to adapt in order to optimize overall success. Strong understanding of position of physicians/medical providers in respect to clients; life-long student of the health sciences and medicine. Proven track record of stellar work ethic and devotion to team goals at every step along the journey.

Expertise

- Full-Stack Web Development
- SQL Queries & Data Modeling
- Strong Analytical/Critical Thinking Skills
- Ability to Learn New Technologies Quickly
- Application Development & Collaboration
- Debugging/Troubleshooting
- Understanding of Healthcare Industry
- Fluency in Medical Terminology

Professional Experience

UI Developer, iVoyant LLC, AT&T Cricket, Atlanta, GA

Feb 2020 to Present

Working mostly as a React Developer for AT&T Cricket in a contract role through iVoyant LLC.

Project Highlights:

Will handle maintenance and development of tasks related to front-end.

Junior Developer, Project Cost Solutions, Atlanta, GA

Feb 2020 to Present

Currently on a one month trial as the lead front-end developer for a subsidiary of Project Cost Solutions called Construction Check Inc. in Decatur, GA.

Project Highlights:

Working with Vue.js front-end; back-end is Java using Spring-Boot with a MySQL database.

React Intern, HEARBK, Atlanta, GA

Dec 2019 to Present

Collaborated remotely with lead developer on two-person development team to build mobile application for Atlanta-based startup intending to provide a platform for aspiring artists to be heard by uploading their music and gaining recognition from top music influencers and fans.

Project Highlights:

- Worked with MERN-stack to make responsive and interactive mobile application.
- Continuing assistance in any role, including maintenance and troubleshooting.

Professional Experience (continued):

Partner and Manager, KIM FAMILY LLC, Ellicott City, MD

Jun 2008 to Present

Kim Family LLC is a family real-estate investment and management business.

Project Highlights:

 Aiding all efforts to manage assets effectively, including financial matters, research and decision-making, and daily maintenance.

Assistant Manager, THE TUTORING CENTER, Johns Creek, GA

Nov 2018 to May 2019

Assisted owner of tutoring center franchise specializing in instruction of K-12/SAT/ACT students.

Project Highlights:

- Coordinated all tutor, ran front desk, opened and cleaned center daily.
- Taught whenever necessary, including SAT/ACT at times.

Senior Analyst Advisor, IFPA INC., Teaneck, NJ

Jan 2017 to Nov 2017

Junior Analyst

Sep 2016 to Dec 2016

Managed company database and contributed to inventory management efforts. IFPA is a large-scale, worldwide parts-manufacturer and distributer, and the main supplier for Herman Miller.

Project Highlights:

- Aided in research efforts regarding product development and cost allocation.
- Attended meetings and gave presentations regarding research findings.

Healthcare Experience

PRN/Tech, CCDDC, Westminster, MD

Aug 2015 to Oct 2016

Briefly worked with 10+person patient-care unit of Carroll County Digestive Disease Center to gain work experience during nursing school.

Project Highlights:

Learned how to prioritize and multi-task work duties properly in facilitating optimal teamwork.

Student, Registered Nursing Program, HCC, Columbia, MD

Jan 2015 to May 2016

Three semesters of the RN program at Howard Community College; I was unhappy and did not enjoy the program while I was in it, so I decided to pursue a career change.

Project Highlights:

- Coordinated with nurses to provide full patient-care throughout acute/long-term care facilities.
- Practiced proper documentation methods and adhered to specific healthcare provider protocol.

Education

Howard Community College, Columbia, MD UMBC, Baltimore, MD

Bachelor of Arts in Biology, GPA: 3.296, Aug 2012

Boston College, Chestnut Hill, MA

Software Development Portfolio

Kim Family LLC, demo, website, github

Feb 2020

- Future Kim Family LLC site so far includes an About page, media container, and contact form.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, React, and Redux.

HearBK Mobile, demo, website

Jan 2020

- Music feedback app includes premium/basic users, payment methods, media uploads, more.
- MERN-stack.

PeachtreeData.com, demo, website, github

Sep 2019

- Wrote social-media/life-database site with connections, newsfeed, media-page, notepad, more.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, React, and Redux.

OWRPG, demo, github

Jul 2019

- Wrote large-scale, multi-layered RPG game incorporating the video game Overwatch.
- Python.

Technology Summary

Applications: VSCode, VSB, Atom, Adobe XD, Postico, Postman, Microsoft Office, Medical

Mastermind, gGastro

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass, SQL, Python, C#

Frameworks: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Redux.js, Bootstrap

Other: jQuery, RESTful API, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Trello,

Jenkins, AWS (EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, Amplify, more), Heroku, Netlify, NGINX,

Apache2, PM2

Leadership and Awards

Phi Theta Kappa Honors Society, Howard Community College, Mar 2015 Secretary of Student Government, Howard Community College, Aug 2013 to Dec 2013 Co-chair of Student Senate, Howard Community College, Aug 2013 to Dec 2013 Sigma Alpha Lambda National Leadership and Honors Organization, UMBC, Aug 2009 Golden Key International Honors Society, UMBC, Sep 2008